♪♪（太鼓）
Tailed Beast Counting Song!
（ナルト）『尾獣数え唄』
はじまり　はじまり！
All right, here we go!
One, "sleep is better than humans,"
says Shukaku
♪♪「一つ　人より」
ONE TAIL SHUKAKU / GAARA
One, "sleep is better than humans,"
says Shukaku
♪♪「居眠り守鶴」
Two, burning in fire, Matatabi
♪♪「二つ　ファイヤー
燃えてる又旅」
TWO TAILS MATATABI / YUGITO NI'I
Two, burning in fire, Matatabi
Three, leave the water to Isobu
♪♪「三つ　水なら」
THREE TAILS ISOBU / YAGURA
Three, leave the water to Isobu
♪♪「任せろ　磯撫」
Four, hot as lava, Son Goku
♪♪「四つ　溶岩
あついぜ孫悟空」
FOUR TAILS SON GOKU / ROSHI
Four, hot as lava, Son Goku
Five, always on the run, Kokuo
♪♪「五つ
いつでも」
FIVE TAILS KOKUO / HAN
Five, always on the run, Kokuo
♪♪「駆け足
穆王」
♪♪「六つ
無理せず」
Six, taking it easy and
not in a hurry, Saiken
SIX TAILS SAIKEN / UTAKATA
Six, taking it easy and
not in a hurry, Saiken
♪♪「アワてず
犀犬」
Seven, the flying leaf insect,
Chomei
♪♪「七つ　ナナフシ
空飛ぶ重明」
SEVEN TAILS CHOMEI / FUU
Seven, the flying leaf insect,
Chomei
Eight, "Yeah!" is all it needs,
Gyuki
♪♪「八つ　やっぱり」
EIGHT TAILS GYUKI / KILLER BEE
Eight, "Yeah!" is all it needs,
Gyuki
♪♪「ウィーだぜ　牛鬼」
Nine, "ko-kon" cries
the mighty Kurama
♪♪「九つ
ココンと」
NINE TAILS KURAMA / NARUTO UZUMAKI
Nine, "ko-kon" cries
the mighty Kurama
♪♪「最強
九喇嘛」
All the Tailed Beasts have
finally come together
♪♪「とうとうそろった　尾獣の仲間」
♪♪「ちょい　ムズだけどいい名前」
They're a little hard,
but they're nice names
♪♪「みんな　立派な名前だね」
They're all splendid names
♪♪「みんな　すてきな名前だね」
They're all wonderful names
みんなも　九喇嘛と
仲間たちの名前→
Hey everyone!
Please try to learn Kurama
and the others' names, okay?
覚えてくれってばよ！
The Risks of the Reanimation Jutsu
You think you can beat me
with Hashirama's will?
（マダラ）柱間が死んで残した
その意志とやらで→
俺に勝てると？
Power is not will.
（マダラ）力とは　意志ではなく
物質の起こす事象のことだ。
Power is only the ability
to make things happen.
You're wrong!
（綱手）違う！　死者の意志が→
The will of the dead
shows its power
残された者を突き動かし
力を現す！
in those they left behind!
私の作った医療忍術も
その意志から生まれ→
I used that will to develop
my Medical Ninjutsu.
医療忍者と掟が構築された！
From there, Medic Ninja and
Medical Laws were established!
Rule One! A Medic Ninja must
never give up on treatment
第一項　医療忍者は決して
隊員の命　尽きるまで→
until their patient's dying breath.
治療を諦めてはならない！
Rule Two! A Medic Ninja must
never go to the frontlines!
第二項　医療忍者は決して
最前線に立ってはならない！
Rule Three!
第三項　医療忍者は決して
小隊のなかで→
A Medic Ninja should always be
the last of their platoon to die!
最後まで死んではならない！
弟子たちに教えたのは
ここまでだ。
This is what I teach my students.
But there is actually
one more rule…
だが　掟はもうひとつある。
Rule Four!
第四項　忍法　創造再生→
A Medic Ninja who masters
the Ninja Art of Mitotic Regeneration,
the 100 Healings…
百豪の術を極めし
医療忍者のみ→
上記の掟を破棄できる！
may break the first three rules!
（メイ）なっ！
The 100 Healings Jutsu?
百豪の術だと？
聞いたこともない。
I've never heard of it.
私だけの禁術…。
It's a Forbidden Jutsu that
applies only to me.
つまり　私だけは
戦えるってことだ！
Which means,
I am the only Medic Ninja
allowed to battle!
花粉は　塵遁で消し飛んだが→
The Particle Style Jutsu may
have dissipated the pollen…
But adding one Medic Ninja
won't make any difference…
医療忍者が　１人増えたところで。
Four wasn't working,
so we'll try five!
４人でダメなら　５人でいく。
Don't you dare think
I'm an ordinary Medic Ninja!
私をただの医療忍者だと
思うなよ！
She's not as fast as the Raikage…
《スピードは　雷影以下》
Let's go!
（エー）いくぞ！
But her power is greater than his!
《パワーは　雷影以上か》
火遁　豪火滅失！
Fire Style…
Majestic Demolisher Flame!
Water Style: Water Pillar!
《水遁　水陣柱！
Water Style!
Water Dragon Missile!
水遁　水龍弾！》
Weighted Boulder!
《オオノキ：加重岩！》
《エー：雷虐水平チョップ！》
Lateral Bolt of Pain! Chop!
確かに　か弱い女ではないな。
I admit…
You're not weak, woman.
だが…。
However…
お前が　でしゃばり死ねば
他の影も終わりだぞ。
If you step in and die here,
all the other Kage will die.
Since you're the only one
who can heal them.
回復役は
貴様だけのようだしな。
That's if I die.
それは　私が死ねばの話だ。
柱間…　お前が
何を残したかは知らんが…。
Hashirama…
I don't know what
you left behind…
But this falls far short
of your abilities.
この程度…
お前には　遠く及ばん…。
If you were going to let
your underlings take over,
どうせ　下っ端に
引き継がせるなら→
俺のように　復活のやり方でも
教えておくべきだったな…。
you should have taught them
how to resurrect you too…
お前が死んで残ったものは→
All that's left of you is
the life force of your cells
俺に　へばりつく
細胞の生命力でしかない。
that cling to me.
弟が死んで残ったものは→
All that's left of
my little brother is
the Visual Prowess of his eyes,
which are now mine.
俺の両眼の瞳術しかない。
だから…。
That's why…
だから　違うと言っている！
I said you're wrong!
引き継がれるものが
あるとすれば…。
The only thing that is
passed down…
憎しみだけだ。
is hatred.
（ダン）何！？　あのマダラが
穢土転生されたのか！？
What?!
Madara was brought back
with the Reanimation?
（チョウザ）本物のマダラが
出てきた以上→
Now that the real Madara
showed up,
五影も　悠長に構えては
いられなくなりました。
the Five Kage had to step in!
火影として　綱手様も
応戦に出られています。
As the Hokage, Lady Tsunade
has joined the battle as well.
（ダン）綱手が火影！？
あいつ　火影になったのか？
Tsunade is the Hokage?!
She became the Hokage?!
（チョウザ）話してませんでしたっけ？
Did I neglect to tell you?
まあ　綱手様も→
Well, Lady Tsunade went through
quite a lot after your passing…
あなたが亡くなられてから
いろいろ　ありましたが…。
結局は
あなたを慕っていましたから…。
But in the end, it just showed
how much she cared about you.
綱手…。
Tsunade…
綱手様が
負けるわけありませんよ！
There's no way Lady Tsunade
will lose!
だからこそ　三忍の中で→
That's why she is
the sole surviving member
唯一　あの歳まで
生きてらっしゃる！
of the Legendary Sannin!
《綱手：お前は死んでいる！
You're already dead!
だから　これ以上
憎しみを　ばらまかないでくれ…》
So don't spread any more hate!
風影　今だ！
Kazekage! Now!
（我愛羅）砂漠層大葬！
Grand Sand Mausoleum!
（我愛羅）封印した！
よし！
He's been sealed!
All right!
お前たちが閉じ込めたのは→
The one you sealed away
is a Wood Style Clone
柱間が使っていた　木遁分身だ。
that Hashirama used to use.
よく出来ていてな…。
It is well made…
かつて　敵として
これを見抜けたのは→
My Visual Prowess made me the only shinobi
who was able to see the ruse…
俺だけだった…。
この瞳力でな。
in the past.
さて…。
Now then…
これで　他の影も終わりだな。
It's over for the rest of you Kage…
（ダン）マダラをナメたら　ダメだ！
Don't underestimate Madara!
やつを止めるには→
The only way to stop Madara
is to stop
大本にいる穢土転生の術者を
止めるしかない！
the one who cast
the Reanimation.
マダラとは
それほどの忍なのですか？
Is Madara…
that powerful a shinobi?
こちらは　五影で
相手をしているというのに。
Even against the Five Kage
facing him now?
Aside from the late First Hokage…
おそらく
マダラと戦って　勝てる忍は…。
今は亡き
初代火影様をおいて　他にない。
there is no one right now
who can defeat Madara in battle…
俺の見張り役と　結界役以外は→
My guard and my barrier sustainer
should stay here.
すぐに　穢土転生の術者捜索に
回したほうがいい！
Everyone else should be going after
the caster of the Reanimation Jutsu!
本部の対応は　どうなっている！
How is HQ dealing with this?
もちろん　全力でやってますが→
Every effort is being made,
but there's been no concrete intel…
これといった情報はなくて…。
《死ぬなよ…　綱手》
Don't die…Tsunade!
《イタチ：口寄せの術！》
Summoning Jutsu!
（サスケ）クソッ！
（イタチ）お前は　ここにいろ。
Damn it!
You stay here.
《あそこか…　つまらぬ結界だ》
There, huh?
What a useless barrier.
（カブト）僕の結界を通り抜け
よく　ここがわかったね。
I'm impressed you were able
to pass through my barrier,
and find this place.
お前に操られている間→
When you were controlling me,
お前のチャクラが
どこから来ているかは→
I was able to pinpoint where
your chakra was coming from.
はっきり感じていた。
これも　術のリスクだ。
That's another risk of this jutsu.
覚えておく必要は
もう　ないがな。
Though you won't need to
remember that for next time.
（カブト）勉強になったよ。
Thanks for the tip.
この術をはね除けられるような
忍は　まずいないから→
I didn't expect any shinobi
to counter this jutsu,
そういう心配は
していなかったからね。
so I didn't even worry about it.
ああ　代わりに覚えておいて
ほしいことがあるんだ。
By the way, there's something
I'd like you to know as well.
この穢土転生の術は
僕を殺しても止まらないけど→
This Reanimation Jutsu
will not come undone
even if you kill me.
この術を止められるのは
僕しかいない。　つまり→
But I am the only one
who can stop it.
In other words…
キミは　僕を殺せないのさ。
You can't kill me.
僕が死ねば　二度と　この術を
止めることができなくなる。
If I die, you'll never be able
to stop this jutsu.
クククク…　アハハハハハ！
運が回ってきたどころじゃ
ないみたいだね！　この僕。
I guess my luck
hasn't run out yet!
思うようにはいかないものだ。
まったく。
Things are not always as
we wish them to be, damn it!
追いついたぞ。
こんなところで　いったい…。
I caught up to you!
What the hell are you doing here?
大蛇丸…　なのか？
Is that…Orochimaru?
（カブト）クク…　少し違う。
You're a little off…
その声は　カブト！
That voice…
Kabuto!
戦争協力の見返りが
このタイミングで　自ら→
It's perfect timing that my compensation
for participating in this war
would show up, on his own,
at this particular moment…
僕の目の前に来ちゃうとはね。
ラッキーだよ。
I am so lucky.
どういう意味だ？
What are you talking about?
なぜ　お前たちが
こんなところで？
What are you both doing here?
（カブト）ややこしい状況だよね。
僕が簡単に説明しようか。
It's rather complicated…
Let me try to explain.
説明していろ。
Go ahead.
そのスキに
穢土転生は止めさせてもらう。
And in the meantime,
I'll stop the Reanimation.
（カブト）この術に弱点はない。
This jutsu has neither
risks nor weaknesses.
リスクもない。　イタチ…　キミのほうには
それを説明したいんだけど。
I want you to understand
that Itachi.
とにかく　キミが動くにも→
Even if you do make a move,
サスケ君が　おとなしく
していないと思うけどね。
I doubt Sasuke will just
sit back and watch.
焦ると止められるものも
止められないかもよ。
If you rush, you may not succeed,
even if it were possible,
conversely…
逆に。
カブト！　質問に答えろ！
Kabuto, answer my question!
（カブト）結局
話さないとダメみたいだね。
I guess I have to tell you,
after all.
そりゃそうだよね　サスケ君。
I mean, while you were asleep
キミが　お兄さんの眼を移植して
寝ている間に→
from having your brother's eyes
transplanted into you…
世界は　とんでもないことに
なっているんだもんね。
something drastic happened
in our world.
トビが戦争を仕掛けたんだな。
Tobi started the war, huh?
少しは知ってるんだ。
まぁ　そうだよね。
So you know a little.
Yes, that's true…
第四次忍界大戦。
The Fourth Great Ninja War…
トビと僕は　火の国　風の国
水の国　土の国→
Tobi and I are at war
with the coalition
of the Nations of Fire, Wind,
Water, Earth and Lightning…
雷の国。　この五大国が
協力して作り上げた→
The Allied Shinobi Force.
忍連合を相手に戦っている。
五大国相手に　お前たちだけで
戦えるはずがないだろう！
There's no way you two can fight
against the Five Great Nations!
それが戦えるんだなぁ！
Oh, but we can…
（カブト）白いほうの
ゼツの量産型が１０万体。
With a hundred thousand
mass-produced White Zetsu!
そして　僕が生み出した
穢土転生の部隊。
And the reanimated battalion
that I created…
金角　銀角。
Kinkaku and Ginkaku!
霧隠れ忍刀七人衆の　前任者たち。
The former members of
the Seven Ninja Swords
Men of the Mist!
二代目土影。
The Second Tsuchikage…
三代目雷影。
The Third Raikage…
二代目水影。
The Second Mizukage…
四代目風影。
The Fourth Kazekage…
そして　うちはマダラ。
And Madara Uchiha…
名前を挙げていったら　キリがない。
I don't have time to mention
all the names.
そこにいる　キミのお兄さんも→
Your brother over there is
also one of the ones I reanimated.
穢土転生で　よみがえった一人さ。
どう？　意外と僕もやるでしょ？
Well?
Not too shabby, huh?
もっとも　すべては
うちはマダラの計画なんだけどね。
Although Madara Uchiha
planned everything.
どういうことだ？
What do you mean?
（カブト）キミたちと同じさ。
忍世界への恨み。
Like you two,
he hated the Shinobi World.
そのために彼は
月の眼計画を立てた。
And so, he came up
with Project Tsuki no Me.
月の眼計画？
Project Tsuki no Me?
十尾を使って　この地上全体に
巨大な幻術をかけるのさ。
A plan to cast a powerful genjutsu
over the entire world
using the Ten Tails.
そして　この地上を支配する。
To control the world.
そのために　ナルト君の九尾と→
For that,
we need Naruto's Nine Tails
キラービーの八尾が
どうしても必要なのさ。
and Killer Bee's Eight Tails.
今頃　それを手に入れるために→
And just about now…
マダラは戦場を
暴れ回っているんじゃないかな。
Madara is causing a ruckus
on the battlefield in order to get them.
さて…　次は　どいつにするかな。
Now then, who's next…?
ぬお～っ！
おりゃ～！
（マダラ）なぜ　お前が動ける？
How can you move?
だから　私は違うと言ったはずだ。
Like I told you, I'm different!
Regeneration without weaving signs…
（マダラ）印を使わぬ再生体…　そうか。
So that's the real power of your jutsu
mentioned in Rule Four.
それが　第四項の
お前の術の能力というわけか。
柱間の能力と同じだな。
It's just like Hashirama's power.
I wanted to catch you off guard
with this, but…
これで　スキを
作ったつもりだったんだがな。
You can't kill me with
my own jutsu.
俺の術で　俺をやれるか。
I can kill you, with my jutsu!
《オオノキ：わしの術ならやれる！》
All right!
よ～し！
Have you gone senile, Ohnoki?
（マダラ）ボケたか？　オオノキ。
輪廻眼は
すべての術を　吸収する。
The Rinnegan can absorb
all jutsu.
Ninjutsu like that will
not work against me!
俺に　その手の忍術は通用しない。
To kill me, you need to hit me
hard physically and seal me.
俺をやるなら　直に殴り倒し→
封印するしかないと
わかっているだろう？
You know that.
さっきは　わしの塵遁で
お前の胸をかすめた。
My Particle Style grazed
your chest earlier…
原界剥離の術が
通じぬはずがない！
There's no way that the Atomic
Dismantling Jutsu didn't work!
Oh that…
あれか…。　あれは　柱間の顔を
お前らに見せつけたくなってな。
I just wanted to show you
all Hashirama's face.
お前らの士気を
下げてやるつもりだったんだが→
I wanted to reduce your morale…
But it seems it had the opposite effect…
It boosted your morale instead.
逆に士気を
上げてしまったようだな。
一つ　質問をする。
Let me ask you a question.
While it doesn't change the fact
木遁分身で　私たち５人を
出し抜いたことには→
that you outwitted us with
the Wood Style Clone…
変わりはないが
見方を変えれば→
But from another angle,
分身して身代わりを
出さなければならないほど→
you could say we managed
to corner you
into having to substitute
a clone for yourself.
追い詰められたとも言える。
違うか？
Am I wrong?
（マダラ）さすがに　５対１だからな。
It is five against one, after all…
Even if it is five-to-one,
we must win, no matter what.
５対１でも
勝たなければならないの。
卑怯とは言わないでくださいよ。
Don't call it unfair!
In truth, it is a testament
to your might!
それだけ　あなたの強さを
認めてあげてるってことですから。
（メイ）あなたは　うちはマダラです。
You are Madara Uchiha!
卑怯とは言わぬ。　５人で１人。
It's not unfair.
Five-to-one… It's just the right ratio
for playing games.
遊ぶには　ちょうどいい。
これで　５対１だ。
Now it's five-to-one.
Don't say this is unfair.
卑怯とは　ぬかすなよ。
お前らは五影だ。
You are the Five Kage.
さて　一つ質問をする。
So now I've got
a question for you…
そいつら分身が
スサノオを使う　使わない→
Would you like these clones
to use Susano'o or not?
Your choice.
どちらがいい？
ってのが　戦争の話。
So that's the story of the war…
だが　どうして　穢土転生で
よみがえったあんたが→
But what is a Reanimation
like you doing here?
こんなところにいる？
あんたの殺気は本物だ。
Your intent to kill is real.
理由は簡単だ。
俺は　こいつに操られていない。
The reason is simple…
I'm not under his control.
（カブト）確かに　そのとおり。
You're absolutely right.
さすが　うちはイタチだよね。
まさか　穢土転生の術に→
I must hand it to you,
Itachi Uchiha.
Imagine, overwriting
the Reanimation Jutsu
自分の幻術を上書きするなんて
普通は考えつかない。
with your genjutsu…
Normally, one wouldn't
even think of that.
あいにく　俺は→
Sorry, but I hate taking orders.
誰かに命令されるのが
嫌いなんでな。
その点は　僕も同調する。
Well, I agree with you there.
You haven't answered
all my questions!
まだ俺の質問に
すべて答えていない！
なんでも聞けば誰かが
答えてくれるって考えは→
Just because you asked
doesn't mean
you're going to get a reply.
いかがなもんかとは思うけど。
まあ　アカデミーの頃から人気者の
キミらしい傾向だけどね。
You haven't changed
from the days
when you were the popular one
at the Academy.
俺らしい傾向とは…
力ずくってことか？
Meaning…I'm still forceful?
Just kidding!
冗談さ。
どうやらキミのお兄さんは…。
Looks like your big brother here…
お前を殺しに来た。
らしいよ。
I came to kill you.
You heard him.
Reanimation… You got a hold
of a silly Forbidden Jutsu.
穢土転生…。
つまらぬ禁術を持ち出したな。
But you see,
thanks to this jutsu,
おやおや。　この術のおかげで
キミたちは→
you siblings get to have
a touching reunion.
感動の再会ができているのに。
少しは感謝してほしいな。
I was hoping for
a little gratitude here.
穢土転生は
心まで操れるわけじゃない。
Reanimation can't control
the heart.
お前は浄化した魂を冒涜し→
You've desecrated souls
that were purified
必要のない悲しみと憎しみを
ばらまき続けている。
and continue to spread
unnecessary sadness and hate.
死者たちが戦う苦しみが
お前に　わかるか？
Can you understand the pain
felt by the dead who
are forced to fight?
The pain of the living
is even greater.
生き残った者たちの
気持は　なおさらだ。
やっと乗り越えた
嘆きと悲しみを。
After finally getting over
the grief and sadness…
your jutsu has stirred
those feelings again!
お前の術は　ぶり返した。
へぇ～。　ちょっとビックリだな。
Well...
I'm a little surprised…
うちは一族を皆殺しにした
キミに→
that someone who slaughtered
the entire Uchiha Clan
そんな優しい心があったとはね。
has such a tender heart…
それともキミが
それを後悔してるって話かな？
Does it mean you regret it?
だったら僕には興味がないけど。
If so, I'm not interested.
何とでも言え。
ここでお前は終わりだ。
Say whatever you want.
You die here.
Sasuke…
サスケ君。
You want to bring down Itachi,
（カブト）キミはうちは一族の敵である
イタチを　また倒したい。
the bane of the Uchiha,
once again, don't you?
Since I brought him back
to this realm.
僕がこの世に
転生させちゃったからね。
つまりサスケ君と僕にとっての
今のイタチは邪魔な存在。
I
ということになるよね？
どうだろう。
ここは　一つ協力して→
このイタチを倒そうじゃないか。
同じ蛇の力を持ち
同じ師を…。
あれを師と呼ぶ気はない。
それにお前は
何も知らないようだな。
俺は今　イタチと話をするために
ここまで追ってきた。
なら　キミは今　どっちの味方だい？
なぜだ！？
こいつは大蛇丸と同じ。
だとしたら　俺の敵だ！
そして今は
あんたの敵でもあるんだろ！？
わかった。　話は　あとでしてやる。
代わりに　まずは　こいつを倒す。
ただし　殺すな。
（イタチ）穢土転生の術者を
殺してしまっては→
術は永久に解けない。
まずはそいつを
俺の月読にかけ→
その術を止める方法を聞き出す。
そして　月読にはめたまま
こいつを俺が操り→
俺が　この術を解く。
流暢に僕の倒し方を
しゃべってくれちゃって。
口で言うほど
うまくいけばいいけど→
この術には
弱点もリスクもないって　さっき…。
（イタチ）どんな術にも
弱点となる穴がある。
ん？
（イタチ）この術の弱点とリスクは…。
この俺の存在だ。
イタチ。　あんたはいつも俺に→
「今度だ　あとでだ」と
ウソをつき　あげく死んだ。
だから　今度こそ
約束は守ってもらう。
性格は死ぬまで変わらないが
俺は一度死んでいる。
そのつもりだ。
兄弟で　僕を仲間はずれですか。
おもしろい。
皆様　お変わりございませんか？
美空ひばりです。
では最後まで　ごゆっくり→
お楽しみください。
『木曜８時のコンサート
名曲！　にっぽんの歌』。
２時間スペシャル！